[Blood River]
[Based on the novel of the same name from Zhou Munan's Youth in Jianghu series]
[Available on fanqienovel.com & bkneng.com]
[Episode 31]
We will help Your Highness
wipe their power from the realm.
That's our offer.
I wonder
if it's enough for you.
Tang Linghuang is our...
friend.
He's also Lianyue's senior.
Naturally,
his life matters greatly to us.
If you can help us
rescue him,
and purge the puppet poison in him,
we'll owe you a great favor.
As for what you said,
borrowing my light
to light Blood River's path...
it's an honor
for me.
I believe
you can bring the jianghu
a brand-new
Blood River.
Not bad.
That's a decent ending.
This isn't the end.
It's only the beginning.
When Blood River is finally accepted
by the world,
Master Mu,
what's the first thing you want to do?
What I want most...
The first thing
is to pass the headship
to Yumo.
The first thing
is to hand it off?
My duty
is to lead the Mu family
into the light.
Clearly,
I've done that.
As for
the road ahead,
that's for them to decide.
My second thing
is to go to Wangchengshan Sect.
I'll meet
the Profound Sword Deity I admire most.
And I'll eat
a peach he planted himself.
Then...
stay at Mount Wangcheng to cultivate?
I did think so once,
but...
probably not.
Why not?
Because cultivation demands cutting off love,
and I can't.
My third thing
is to tell Xuewei...
I like her,
and...
I've liked her for many years.
The previous generation of the Mu family
in Blood River
were terrors that made people quake.
So how come your lot
think only of romance?
Sir,
why are your hands so cold?
When did you learn the Frost Palm?
I didn't.
Changhe...
Let's head back to the Clinic.
Master,
are you sure
this tonic won't overwhelm
Changhe's body?
It's way too tonifying.
It's all blazing yang herbs.
No matter.
Su Changhe can take it.
Okay.
You're burning, then freezing.
How is this possible?
What's this?
Changhe,
my master told you to drink this.
I'm not drinking it.
Does this look fit for a human to drink?
I tasted it.
It looks black
but tastes sweet.
Without that medicine,
you'll sleep an hour
and wake freezing,
another hour
and wake burning.
Then you won't sleep again,
because you'll feel
ants crawling all over you.
Mighty Patriarch of Blood River
ever suffered like that?
Feels like being thrown back into the Furnace.
The Prince of Langya
is off.
Maybe...
he cultivates an extreme-cold style?
That palm you took earlier
hurt you with Frost Qi.
His skills aren't weak.
But if his palm could hurt me this bad,
what right do we have
to bargain with him?
My Hell Palm
draws in the opponent's Qi
in a clash of palms,
and strikes it back.
So the stronger the foe, the harder it hits.
But the Prince of Langya's Qi
carries poison.
What kind of poison?
It's frost poison.
That's right.
If it were Frost Qi alone,
I'd just absorb it and strike it back.
But the frost poison is tricky.
With one palmful I drew in,
it started rampaging
all through my body.
He poisoned you?
No, he didn't.
The moment he came in,
I sensed something off
in his look.
He was invaded by frost poison himself.
He hasn't long to live.
Oh, really?
But,
isn't he a prince?
With so many imperial physicians,
how is he still afflicted?
I heard two years ago,
he led a southern campaign.
Nanjue sent
five martial arts grandmasters to kill him.
All five were cut down,
but one of them
had reached the Free-Heaven level
and practiced the Demonic Frost Art, Moon-Yin Finger.
Maybe the rumor is true.
No wonder
he's so desperate to work with us.
Seems he's cornered too.
Can this frost poison
be cured?
I'd need to take his pulse
to be sure,
but from how he looked earlier,
he's likely at the point
of beyond remedy.
Even if once
there was a chance to treat it,
by now
there's at best a sliver of hope.
As a man soon to die,
what would he want from us?
Maybe he wants our hand
to purge Tianqi City
of those plotting unrest.
Before he dies, he wants
to clear every threat
for his elder brother.
That's his aim.
So noble as that?
If I were dying,
why care about tomorrow?
The world
would have nothing to do with me.
I'm going into seclusion.
Seclusion?
That frost poison nearly crippled me,
and it ties to my Hell Palm
at the ninth level.
I failed to break that threshold,
so the backlash hit this hard.
Once I reach the ninth,
any frost or flame poison
will be easy to dispel.
All right.
Then leave to me
the other affairs for now.
Don't rush.
The Prince of Langya is at death's door.
They're the ones who should worry,
not us.
If we send Tang Linghuang back
safe and sound in just a few days,
who knows
what'll happen next.
Who are you?
Su Changli
of the Su family.
Yong said
someone would visit today.
Is that you?
Yes.
I'm Patriarch Su Changhe's younger brother.
From now on,
I'll relay messages
between the patriarch and the first prince.
[To Dian Ye, personal]
[Prince of Langya bears frost poison, near beyond cure]
Is what's written here true?
I only pass messages.
What is written
was penned by Blood River's Patriarch.
I haven't read the contents.
If you doubt it,
go doubt it yourselves.
Don't ask us.
You people of Blood River,
what do you really want?
You be emperor of Tianqi City,
and we'll be king of the jianghu.
Miss, have a look.
[Soft cool breezes stir]
[Chill cold dew drips]
Have a look.
[Cold Dew today]
All from noted masters.
[Season turns, days grow cold]
[Layer up, keep warm]
Come take a look.
[He-Yu Clinic]
Morning, Miss Bai!
[Kind Heart, Skilled Hands]
Second Master Tu.
You're looking well.
Thanks for your prescription.
Now,
I feel strength to spare!
Before, a few steps
left me winded.
Now,
I can climb ten floors in one go
without panting.
Good.
But you still need to breathe.
Come on,
bag a few more doses
to keep him in tune.
Got it, Master.
With autumn winds up,
internal heat flares easily.
Thank you, Miss Bai.
Much obliged!
No need.
You're here for Su Muyu, right?
He went out early today.
No,
I'm here for you, Miss Bai.
[Li Residence]
Are officials in Tianqi City
all this rich?
How does this compare
with your manor?
Mine's bigger, of course.
Then he isn't that rich.
Because the Commander's manor
is only this big,
the Deputy Commander's
can only be smaller.
That's officialdom for you.
Both of you, please.
Master.
This is Second Master Tu of Thousand-Gold Tower.
And this is the physician
he brought.
We've met.
I had the honor to visit you
with my elder brother.
You brought a physician this young?
Yes,
I'm this young.
Don't let Miss Bai's age fool you, Sir.
She's from...
My skills speak for themselves.
Okay.
Sir,
saving lives
is a matter of utmost urgency.
Don't block us here.
Let me in to treat him, quickly.
How do you know
the patient is in that room?
Because I can hear
his breathing inside,
nine short, one long,
the long ending with a cough of blood.
What does that mean?
He's dying.
This way, please.
What's that smell?
Mr. Li,
we're here to treat you.
up you get.
Wake up.
Is this soul-loss?
Soul-loss?
If only it were.
What's his condition?
He's alive.
Miss Bai,
quit with the cryptic talk.
He sprang up
just like that.
Of course he's alive!
It's tricky.
Take this.
Miss Bai,
what for?
I'll take it back and refine medicine.
This case defies a quick prescription.
I need time to work it out.
Let's go.
Careful, Miss Bai!
What a hassle.
Miss Bai.
What's going on?
Nothing.
He's only asleep.
Second Master Tu,
let's go.
Miss!
Hold on!
How is my son's illness?
His condition
won't be cured in a snap.
If it were that simple,
those physicians you hired
would've fixed him already.
But none of them
produced this specific reaction.
That means their skills were lacking.
However,
I can at least let your son
sleep soundly.
Otherwise,
if that state earlier
last another dozen days,
even if he doesn't die,
he'll be a living corpse.
Hey!
Sir, rest easy.
Miss Bai has a plan.
Once the elixir is refined,
Mr. Li's illness
will naturally be cured.
Cured?
What's going on?
I don't know either.
The deputy commander sent men everywhere for physicians,
and one turned up at Blood River's clinic.
By the time we heard,
the physician was already inside.
Don't let her leave.
At once.
Can your people
guarantee this job?
You decide to act?
Let's hope those Blood River folks
don't disappoint me.
Much obliged, Sir.
Guards!
Can you find a cure?
Of course.
But,
it'll take a few days.
If that's the case,
please stay
at my manor a few days.
Sir,
I brought the physician here.
If she wants to leave,
I'm taking her.
If you mean to keep her by force,
there's only one way.
Which is?
Kill me.
You think I don't dare?
Never mind my title
as Second Master of Thousand-Gold Tower.
Today, I'm just Tu Wan.
If you want me dead,
go ahead and try
so long as you can shoulder
the cost.
Fine.
As you wish!
Whether I stay or go
isn't for you to decide.
Come on!
All of you at once.
Let's see
who can keep us here today.
Go!
Who's there?
You knew I'm here?
No.
I guessed.
Who are you?
Physicians heal and save lives.
All should respect them.
Yet you would cage one.
How is that right?
So, you're going to kill me?
If I wanted you dead,
I could do it anytime.
But right and wrong
aren't judged by might.
You stand in the light.
Treasure your power and rank.
Let's go.
Off we go!
Also,
if you want to make trouble
for Second Master Tu later,
then next time we meet,
what I bring you
won't be just sword energy.
What madman are you?
Do you take Tianqi City's Jinwu Guard
for mere decoration?
You're just a swordsman.
You may kill one, kill ten.
But if my Jinwu Guard comes by the thousand,
will you survive?
I don't know if I will,
but you...
will certainly die.
Truly sorry.
I thought
it was a chance
for He-Yu Clinic to make a name in Tianqi.
I didn't expect the Jinwu Guard's deputy commander
to be this unreasonable.
It's fine.
You meant well.
Miss Bai and I will head back.
If the deputy commander
comes after you later,
find us at the Clinic.
Don't be afraid.
We've got your back.
All right.
As for his son's illness,
no need to bother, Miss.
Let them fend for themselves.
They should taste a little hardship.
I'll take my leave.
Mr. Su,
let's go hear some tunes when you're free.
Farewell.
That deputy commander's son
isn't right.
Why?
He bears puppet poison,
but unlike what we saw
in Sihuai City that day.
This one is still alive.
I have a bad feeling.
Maybe Night Crow
is seeping her puppet poison
through all of Tianqi City.
If even here
a deputy commander's son is poisoned,
then elsewhere
others
may be infected too.
Are they trying
to raise a puppet army?
No wonder they've kept quiet
all this time.
Let's return to the Clinic.
I took a drop of his brow-blood.
I'll see if I can refine
an antidote early.
Okay.
Be careful!
What crushing blade aura.
You're Blade Ghost Xu Liuyun.
You're Umbrella Ghost Su Muyu.
Many years ago,
we met once.
Yes.
Shame we met,
yet had no chance
to test each other.
Meeting again in Tianqi City
settles that regret.
You want a fight with me?
Why?
Sent by another,
I've waited for you here.
As for the physician behind you,
her life
will be taken here, today.
So the famed Blade Ghost of Nanjue
let Tianqi's powers
use him?
Didn't expect that.
We're all just blades
in others' hands.
Isn't Blood River the same?
Not anymore.
We're different now.
Miss Bai,
when I clash with him,
find a way to slip out.
I've heard
of the Blade Ghost of Nanjue.
They say his skill rivals a Blade Deity's,
but his ways are too bizarre
to be ranked one.
Be careful.
Rest easy.
No problem.
Since they call you Umbrella Ghost,
I'll gift you a ghost-breaker.
Immortal-slayer!
Without your umbrella,
you can't use the Eighteen-Sword Array.
After all,
that's your deadliest killing art.
My Spring-Rain Swordwork
is enough to kill you.
I see.
You want
to cast off those marks on you,
the title Umbrella Ghost,
the Eighteen-Sword Array...
Do you know
when a killer
will meet
his death?
It's...
when his heart holds
more than killing!
Don't treat me like dead weight!
Now I see
why you're only a Blade Ghost,
not a Blade Deity.
As long as I win,
titles mean nothing!
Horse-Cleaver fells immortals.
Goose-Feather Blade slays saints.
Miao Sabre breaks ghosts.
Precept Blade banishes Buddhas.
Gold-Ring Saber destroys deities.
Be you immortal, Buddha, ghost, deity,
or the greatest sage among men,
all will die beneath my blades!
Fall!
Su Muyu!
I've laid a poison array.
He won't dare get close.
Fight at ease.
Kill him!
What?
I know
why you use so many blades.
You can't drive any single one
to its limit.
Therefore,
you wield them all
to mask your weakness.
You're not wrong.
But I'll kill you
before you shatter the last,
Umbrella Ghost!
Now that Changhe and I lead Blood River,
you should address me as...
Master Su.
All right.
You're worthy of the name!
No one's there?
You really think I'm that foolish?
Miss Bai!
Miss Bai.
Master...
Stop the bleeding for me.
At my waist,
there's a green vial.
Take it out.
It can save my life.
Don't worry.
Miss Bai...
Useless!
You wasted plenty of my Qi.
You didn't use your sword.
With only sword aura and energy,
you killed my disciple at her side.
Seems you care quite a lot
for that lady.
Yet you're merciless
to your disciple.
She can't move now,
and could die any moment.
If you still mean to shield her,
it won't be as easy as before.
Why must you kill her?
She's the one least tied
to this mess.
Dragging her
into this storm,
do you feel guilty?
Wind rises!
Blade-Ruin Array!
It takes time to break
my Blade-Ruin Array.
You won't live to see him.
Die!
You forced the array to save her.
Had you let her go,
you wouldn't be this badly hurt.
What-ifs
are meaningless.
But in the end,
I'm the winner!
This blade's seen years.
Thirty-two years ago,
when I first wandered the jianghu,
I bought it for two taels.
It's broken three times since,
patched and cased,
sixteen years without light.
Now drawn again,
it can take
Master Su's fine head...
Lucky for it, I'd say.
Take my fine head?
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪
♪How many hidden feelings♪
♪Sink in silence deep?♪
♪Searching through the endless nights♪
♪Struggling on the edge of love and pain♪
♪Shadows crossing shadows♪
♪Whose name hides in your eyes?♪
♪When the wind blows, ask not when I shall return♪
♪Ask not when I shall return♪
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪